In the last video, we'll learned how to decrease
在上节视频中 我们学习了如何
an error function by walking along the negative of its gradient.
通过沿着负梯度方向移动来降低误差函数
Now in this video, we're going to learn formulas for these error functions.
在这节视频中 我们将要学习这些误差函数的公式
The two most common error functions for linear regression are the mean absolute error,
线性回归最常见的两种误差函数为平均绝对误差
and the mean squared error.
和均方误差
First, we'll learn the mean absolute error.
首先 我们来学习平均绝对误差
So, here's a point and a line,
这是我们的点和直线
the point has coordinates x, y,
这个点坐标为 (x,y)
and the line is called Y-hat since it's the prediction.
这条直线称为 y-hat 代表预测值
So, our prediction for this point is going to be the point
所以我们对这个点的预测应该是
in the line with the same x coordinate as our point,
直线上的一点 这个点的横坐标为 x
that is the point x, y hat.
这个点的坐标为 (x, y-hat)
This means the vertical distance from the point to the line is y minus y hat,
也就是说点到直线的垂直距离为 y 减去 y-hat
and that's what we'll be calling the error.
这就是我们所说的误差
Notice that this is not the actual distance to
注意这不是点到直线的实际距离
the line since this would be a perpendicular segment,
因为这只是垂线段
but it's the vertical distance from the point to
但是点到直线的垂直距离
the line which is the distance between the point and its prediction.
表示这个点到预测之间的距离
Now, our total error is going to be the sum of
目前我们的误差总值是
all these distances for all the points in our dataset.
我们数据集里这些距离的总和
And sometimes we'll use this as our error,
有时我们这样使用 作为误差
but in this case we'll use the average or the mean absolute error,
但是在这个例子中 我们使用平均绝对误差
which is the sum of all the errors divided by m,
即所有误差的总和除以 M
the number of points in our dataset.
M 为我们数据集中的点数
Using the sum or the average won't change our algorithms,
利用总和或平均数不会改变我们的算法
since that would only scale our error by a constant,
因为我们只是用常数 M 缩小了误差
namely m. Notice something here which is
注意这里表示
that we have an absolute value around the y minus y hat,
我们在 y-yhat 两边用了绝对值符号
the reason is that if the point is on top of the line,
原因在于当点位于直线上方时
the distance is y minus y hat,
距离为 y - y-hat
but if it's under the line then it's y hat minus y.
但是当点位于下方时 距离为 y-hat - y
We want the error to always be positive,
我们希望误差为正数
otherwise negative errors will cancel with positive errors.
否则负数误差会抵消正数误差
Therefore, we take the absolute value of y minus y hat.
因此我们使用绝对值 |y - y-hat|
So, our mean absolute error is the average of all absolute errors or in other words,
所以我们的平均绝对误差是所有绝对误差的平均值
the sum of all these absolute values divided by the number of points,
即这些绝对值的总和除以点数 M
which is m. We're going to plot these error over here in a graph.
我们在图形上绘制这些误差
Obviously as we mentioned before,
显然 正如我们前面提到的
the graph has more dimensions but this is a two-dimensional simplification of that graph.
图表有多个维度 但是这只是图表的二维简化图
As we descend in this graph using gradient descent,
在这个图中我们利用梯度下降法进行下降
we get a better and better line until we find
会得到越来越好的直线
the best possible fit with the smallest possible mean absolute error.
直到我们得到匹配最小平均绝对值的最佳直线